I think my dad couldn't
handle being labeled a thief.
My mom apparently thought
he really did steal it, too.
It made me want to stop believing in people.
I even thought that maybe I'd feel better
if I ended up hating one of my parents.
But years later, my mom let slip that she
regretted not believing him back then.
That's when I realized I should
continue to love them both.
I realized that my belief in people
was one of the good things about me.
Wh-What the hell?
I saw Airi-chan go in there!
C-Could she still be inside?
Hey!
Airi!
Can you hear me, Airi?
Hang in there!
She's heavy!
Hey, Airi!
Shit!
There's no way I can do this!
Manager?
You should never count on a comic artist, huh?
We're going down in one go!
Satoru, go out the back.
Don't get Airi-kun mixed up in this anymore.
I'm taking all the credit!
Will Airi be okay?
But that fire...
Don't tell me he was behind it as well.
Oh, right!
He set the fire to try to kill Airi.
And it looks like I did it.
Airi snuck her phone into my pocket
so the police wouldn't see this text.
That means the killer already knew
Airi's address, or he followed her.
He might be closer than I thought.
I have to look for him.
Either I find him, or I get caught trying.
Hello?
Who is this? Identify yourself.
Fujinuma Satoru.
If you really are Fujinuma Satoru,
then it's a pleasure.
I've been waiting for your call.
Yes, of course.
Not here, though. Let's meet somewhere else.
Right, I haven't introduced myself yet.
Let's save that for when we meet tomorrow.
Because you might be the one
who murdered Fujinuma Sachiko.
Welcome!
Hey, Satoru-kun. Over here.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Sawada, formerly of the TV Ishikari city desk.
Thank goodness. You really are Satoru-kun.
Yeah, you resemble your mother.
It's him.
Since you're probably wondering:
no, I didn't tip off the cops.
I didn't murder your mother, either.
You don't suspect me?
Of course not.
Why?
Because a mother like her
wouldn't have raised a murderer.
I see.
I remembered yesterday that I had it in my pocket.
This has become quite a conundrum.
I have no excuse.
It's also partly my fault since I keep screwing up.
It's pointless to blame yourself
for something after it happens.
Sachiko-san's words.
I always liked them.
Shall we talk about what I discussed
over the phone with her?
Yes, please.
Sawada-kun, do you remember the
serial murder case from 18 years ago?
Of course. Shiratori Jun is on death row,
but he still hasn't admitted his guilt.
Satoru was right about it.
Shiratori-kun didn't do it.
I've realized who the real culprit is.
Let's meet at Koiwa Station tomorrow.
I should've asked for a name.
There's a past incident I want to discuss.
The murder of Hinazuki Kayo-chan.
On the night of March 2nd, 1988,
Kayo was locked in the shed after being beaten up
by her mother and her mother's boyfriend.
She froze to death.
At first, the police suspected the mother
and her boyfriend, thinking they'd hid the body.
But in reality, Kayo disappeared from the shed
sometime between 10 and 11 p.m. on the 2nd.
When her mother noticed she
was gone at 12:30 a.m. on the 3rd,
she called your house and nonchalantly
inquired about Kayo's whereabouts.
It was Shiratori Jun who had kidnapped her.
One piece of evidence provided was that
the rubber boot prints made near the shed
matched with boots found at the Shiratori home.
The official version of events is as follows.
He knocked her out with
blunt force, photographed her,
and took her to a commercial freezer,
where he used a spray to speed up her death.
When her body temperature dropped
to 20 degrees, she was brain-dead.
He then waited 30 minutes
to eliminate any chance of survival
and returned the corpse to the
Hinazuki's shed before sunrise.
Yuuki-san would never do something like that!
A little before Hinazuki Kayo,
Sugita Hiromi and Nakanishi Aya disappeared,
there were serial kidnapping and
murder cases in the next town over too.
The culprit was caught immediately and,
just like Shiratori, denied any wrongdoing.
Now, if we take your current predicament
into account, do you notice a pattern?
People keep ridiculing me as a crazy reporter
who investigates closed cases.
But in reality, none of these cases are closed.
Hinazuki Kayo and Sachiko were both killed
by a man who frames others for his crimes!
And he's in this city right now.
He's one tricky bastard.
By creating additional suspects,
he delays the investigation,
causing eyewitness testimonies to diminish
and the crime scene to deteriorate.
As a result, the trail to him goes cold.
Talk about overreacting.
So Fujinuma Satoru tried to silence her?
He won't be able to get at her now.
But what about her?
Is she an accomplice?
He forced her to help him kill his mother,
and once that was done, he tried to silence her.
How awful. I can't believe he dragged
the girl into his mess like that.
You're wrong.
There's no need for you to apologize, Airi-chan.
Yeah. It was all that stalker's fault,
not yours. You must've been so scared.
That's not what happened, Auntie.
It's okay! I'm sorry we didn't notice anything.
You're wrong.
The police are searching for the culprit.
There's nothing to be afraid of now.
You've got it all wrong.
I can't believe they're going after
Satoru-san for murder and arson.
Who would believe me...
That girl got a text from Sachiko-san's phone?
Yeah.
The news said she suffered light injuries,
but she's probably still in the hospital.
Here's her phone.
I see.
He tried to help the murder investigation
along by framing you for arson.
I'm sure that's partly why,
but I was already the prime suspect.
I don't think he'd go after her,
Katagiri Airi, for just that reason.
Are you saying she was a target herself?
In order to frame me for my mother's murder,
he needed to know when I'd get home from work.
He killed her a little more than a day
after she saw his kidnapping attempt.
In that time frame, he visited
the restaurant and saw our shift schedule.
And Airi must've seen him then.
He might be someone I know too.
I see. So he's someone who'd be able to get behind
the counter in a store to look at the schedule.
We might be able to use this to get to him.
I'm going to the hospital.
O-Okay.
There are reports on the murders
from 18 years ago on my computer.
Have a look.
I theorize that Shiratori Jun suspects
his own father of being the culprit.
It's possible that he refuses to provide any alibis
or evidence because it may incriminate his father,
but in turn it makes it worse for himself.
Sounds like Yuuki-san, all right. He loved his dad.
Students from school had seen Hinazuki Kayo
and Shiratori Jun together on numerous occasions.
Fujinuma Satoru's testimony was ignored,
but the testimonies of the other students were taken into serious consideration.
A list of suspects?
I don't know any of these names
aside from Yuuki-san and his father.
Not to mention, there were only five?
The police presumed that Sugita Hiromi
was killed after being mistaken for a girl.
As a result, the police made a list of five suspects
who weren't acquainted with Sugita Hiromi.
We're doing a folk dance today.
Seriously?
I don't wanna hold hands with some ugly girl.
I'd much rather have Hiromi!
Y-You've got guts!
It's now clear why Hiromi was killed.
The culprit was perfectly aware of his gender,
so he killed him to avoid
being on the list of suspects.
Shiratori Jun was arrested after
someone in the neighborhood reported
that he had been talking to
a third-grade girl who was alone.
Photos taken at the time of Sugita's murder
were found in Shiratori Foods' storeroom,
and the police concluded that
Shiratori Jun had pedophilic tendencies.
They also seized pedophilic
magazines from his room.
He never had stuff like that!
All of it was planted by the killer
to draw attention away from himself!
Where's the list from before Hiromi's death?
The killer's name must be on it!
Katagiri, I'm coming in.
Uh, I'm here to visit.
But first, is the restroom that way?
That's right.
No vacancies... except for room 201.
She's asleep.
I see.
Shit! I'm gonna wet myself!
Pardon my intrusion, Katagiri Airi-san.
Looks like you're not Fujinuma Satoru-san.
I-I'm not. I'm Sawada, his friend.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Airi's mother.
There's no way Satoru-san did it.
He didn't kill his mother.
He didn't try to kill me in a fire, either.
He actually came to save me from the fire!
Your manager was the one who saved you.
You must be confused
after inhaling all that smoke.
I don't know what you've been told,
but they think I could be his accomplice!
It hurts me so much that nobody believes me.
But people are even less likely to
believe Satoru-san, and that hurts me more.
Airi.
Even now, I still feel like
I should've gone after your father.
So off you go.
Don't worry, I believe you.
Damn! I forgot to turn it off!
It was still on! Thank goodness!
Is that you, Airi?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine now.
That aside, can we meet at
the usual place right now?
No, stay away! If you do that, you'll get—
It's all good! I promise I'll come alone!
Go! Is it actually gonna fly?
I can't believe I actually came.
I could've just asked her about
the killer over the phone.
It'll only make things worse for her
if she gets involved any further.
What? It doesn't fly at all!
That's weird. Why won't it fly?
Doing this gives it what's called "aerodynamic lift."
Will that really make it fly?
Yeah.
Whoa! You're right!
It flew towards the river!
It's flying too far!
What's he doing at this hour?
Is he unemployed?
Did Yuuki-san go through this, too?
Here I am, Satoru-san.
Yeah.
I came alone, just like I promised!
I feel bad for worrying that this
might have been a police trap.
I said that out loud...
You damn well should be worried about that!
You're a fugitive, you know.
But I'm happy you believed in me.
Yeah.
The store?
I think that Nishizono guy is the most suspicious.
Nishizono?
I've seen him a couple times.
The manager treats him with respect,
and from the badge he wears,
he's probably a city councilor.
He would've been able to check the schedule,
and it wouldn't be a stretch
for him to know where we live.
I've even exchanged pleasantries with him.
Nishizono? I didn't see that name
on the list. Could it be an alias?
But surely you can't sit on
the city council using an alias.
He probably tried to kill me
because I know what he looks like.
Damn it! It's not coming together!
The final piece of the puzzle won't fit!
Satoru-san, I understand how you feel,
but you can't beat yourself up over it.
I have unfinished business from a long time ago.
Oh, I'm talking about a story
for a comic I came up with.
It's a story about a reaper who makes
a scheduling error and ends up killing a child.
He tries desperately to undo his mistake,
but the more he tries, the more misfortune
he brings to the people he comes in contact with.
He intends to do the right thing,
but everything he does hurts other people.
You mean to say he's like you right now?
Wouldn't you agree?
Are you stupid?
Well, I'm not hurt.
And that stuff about other people was
just the reaper jumping to conclusions.
I think the reaper should have more faith in himself.
Everything that's happening
right now is just work in progress.
The ending is a ways off,
and nobody knows how it'll turn out.
I'm so lucky to have met you, Airi.
I said that out loud!
You're Fujinuma Satoru, correct?
Satoru-san!
Stay out of this!
Airi!
Fujinuma Satoru,
you are under arrest for murder and
attempted murder resulting from arson.
Suspect apprehended at 1650 hours.
Why?! Satoru didn't do it!
There's no way he would have!
Satoru-san!
I knew that my relationship with Airi would
cease to be, either through arrest or Revival.
And now that time has come.
I'll never see her again.
There's something I have to do...
I'm so sorry, Satoru-san!
I probably led these people here,
even though I promised to come alone!
I have to give Airi what I wanted to give her.
Just like she did for me.
I'm sorry! So sorry! I'm so sorry...
It's all my fault...
What would a superhero say at a time like this?
Isn't it hard to fight all alone?
You've got it all wrong, Airi.
It's because you believed in me...
that I can keep fighting.
Thank you, Airi. I'm glad I believed in you.